Guide to the Carla Stellweg Papers M1752
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 10. Accession 2015-145. Additional Materials
  - El Arte Simulacral del Fetiche Critico, review of the show at CA2M, Madrid, Spain, 2010 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    The exhibition was curated by El Colectivo Espectro Rojo, Mariana Botey, Cuauhtemoc Medina et al. It also was an exhibition at Museo Universitario Arte Contemporáneo, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Mexico D.F.
  - Gallerists and the Workplace - Carla Stellweg essay for, Taking Aim: the business of being an artist today, catalog and exhibition at the Bronx Museum, 2010 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    The catalog was published by Fordham University Press.
  - Testimonios: Desdeelotrolado - Carla Stellweg essay and co-edited catalog, Lingua Franca: Arte Contemporaneo un Continente llamado América Latina, 2010-2011 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    The catalog was published by Landucci, S.A. de C.V., for UBS to distribute among its VIP Private Clients Mexico, D.F. Carla Stellweg's essay appears on pp.79-112. Materials include drafts of text, correspondence, the catalog and a Compact Disc.
  - Carla Stellweg essay for The Dublin Contemporary International Art Exhibition (part 1 of 2), 2011 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    Included is related reviews, notes, Willie Doherty press packet, etc. Carla Stellweg essay titled Terrible Beauty was published in Arte al Dia International Issue #137, Nov. 2011 – Jan. 2012 (pp. 94-97).
  - Carla Stellweg essay for The Dublin Contemporary International Art Exhibition (part 2 of 2), 2011 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Materials Carla Stellweg edited and annotated for James Oles' book, Art and Architecture in Mexico, 2012 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    James Oles’ book Art and Architecture in Mexico, was published by Thames & Hudson Ltd, London, 2013. Carla Stellweg included in Acknowledgements and mentioned in Chapter IV: Mexicanism Redux, p. 379
  - Catalog, Basado en una Historia/Based on a True Story, for a group exhibition of the same name curated by Yael Rosenblut at the Museo de Salvador Allende, Chile, 2012 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    The exhibition featured sophisticated video artists whose works incorporated elements of film in order to challenge conventional narrative structures while at the same time expanding the creative limits of the moving image. The catalog was edited by Alan Meller with Carla Stellweg text, Patrick Jolley: una Vida Idiosincrática y Peripatética appearing on pp. 9-12. Published in Chile: Museo de la Solidaridad Salvador Allende, 2012.
  - School of Visual Arts trip to Cuba for Habana Biennial, 2012 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    Preparation materials as well as program of Spring Break 2012 The School of Visual Arts, New York, Honor Students trip to Cuba for the Habana Biennial, visiting artist studios, museums, galleries, the film institute, etc.
  - Xi Fei exhibition catalog, In the Belly of the Beast: A Selection of Paintings and Works on Paper by Xi Fei, curated by Carla Stellweg at White Box, 2012 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    The catalog was published by Goldman Art Management, Inc. NY. Carla Stellweg text appears on pp. 6-9.
  - Program, invite and other materials for, Fixing Shadows: Milagros de la Torre in Dialogue with Charles Traub and Carla Stellweg, as part of the School of Visual Arts' Art in the First Person lecture series, 2012 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    The program was in conjunction with the exhibition Observed: Milagros de la Torre, curated by Edward J. Sullivan at the Americas Society Gallery, NY (February 8 – April 14, 2012). Digital supplement: Video of discussion.
  - Catalog, program, loan contract and other materials for, ¡Lo Carnavalesco!, An exhibition at Mycellium Ingenium, Mexico D.F., 2012 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    PISO 51 (March 8 – April 29, 2012), curated by Sarina Basta who invited Carla Stellweg to curate a section within the larger exhibition with ephemera, mail art, artist books and other artworks from the Carla Stellweg collection. A SELECTION OF THESE MATERIALS PURCHASED BY MoMA LIBRARY, MILAN HUGSTON.
  - School of Visual Arts trip to Oaxaca, Mexico, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    Flight info, schedule, and corresponding materials.
  - Carla Stellweg presentation at the Museo Nacional de Plata, Taxco, Guerrero, Mexico, 2013 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    Outline, documents and other materials relating to the 76a Feria Nacional de la Plata. Digital supplement: PowerPoint Presentation.
  - Latino Art Now! Symposium organized by SALALM at the Smithsonian Latino Center, Washington D.C., 2013 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    Schedule, information catalog and documents/materials from the symposium. The conference was a biennial forum for artists, historians, scholars, as well as educators, including Carla Stellweg as a moderator for Session 9: The City as Site and Source.
  - Carla Stellweg lecture for Edward Sullivan's Mexican Art seminar at New York University's Institute of Fine Arts, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and images script as well as video links plus notes relating to Carla Stellweg lecture for Edward Sullivan’s Mexican Art seminar at the NY University’s Institute of Fine Arts, as part of the Colloquium on Art in Spain and Latin America series coordinated by Professors Jonathan Brown, Robert Lubar, and Edward Sullivan.
  - Vistas Latinas: Collective Solutions and Strategies in conjunction with the exhibition, Vistas Latinas: Archives of a Collective, at Hunter College Gallery, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, catalog, notes and presentation texts from the panel discussion titled, Vistas Latinas: Collective Solutions and Strategies, in conjunction with the exhibition, Vistas Latinas: Archives of a Collective, 1989 – 2014 (March 7 – 28, 2014), Hunter College Gallery, New York. Opening remarks by Carla Stellweg – Digital Supplements: DVD and video of panel
  - Carla Stellweg presentation for, Terence Gower in Conversation with Claire Bishop, as part of the School of Visual Arts' Art in the First Person lecture series, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    Documents pertaining to Carla Stellweg presentation for Terence Gower in Conversation with Claire Bishop as part of The School of Visual Arts, New York, Art in the First Person lecture series (Tuesday, February 11, 2014) – Digital Supplements: video of panel
  - Carla Stellweg presentation for, Displaying Human Rights: Museums, Archives and Post-Dictatorship in Latin America, at Columbia University, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    Digital Supplements: PowerPoint presentation and video of panel.
  - Invite and schedule for, The America's Revealed: Collecting Colonial and Modern Art in the United States, at the Frick Center for the History of Collecting, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Invite and independent contract for, Seemoriah, a performance piece by Caryn Moriah at Casita Maria Center for Arts and Education, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Catalog for Rodolfo Edwards' exhibition, Wanderlust, at Galeria Mundo Sur, Santiago, Chile, 2015 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    Carla Stellweg catalog article, The Art of Architectural Disguise: New Paintings by Rodolfo Edwards appears on pp. 4-7.
  - Presentation text, invite and materials for, Galia Solomonoff: Why Art and Architecture Today?, as part of the School of Visual Arts' Art in the First Person lecture series, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    Digital Supplements: video of panel
  - Invites for various exhibitions, including artist Vargas-Suarez UNIVERSAL, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    Invites for various exhibitions including artist Vargas-Suarez UNIVERSAL as well as catalog and extra bibliographical materials for the exhibition, Cosmos Codex: New work by Vargas-Suarez UNIVERSAL, at Movimiento de Arte y Cultura Latino Americana, San José, CA (May 2-August 2, 2014). Carla Stellweg article entitled, Beyond Function and Form: The Art of Rendering the Invisible Visible, appears on pp. 4-9.
  - Presentation for, Pablo Leon de la Barra in Conversation with Carla Stellweg, for the School of Visual Arts' Art in the First Person lecture series, 2014 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    Presentation text, invite and extra materials for Pablo León de la Barra in conversation with Carla Stellweg, as part of the series Why Art and Architecture Today? at the School of Visual Arts, New York, for the Art in the First Person lecture series and in conjunction with the Guggenheim exhibition curated by León de la Barra entitled, Under the Same Sun: Art from Latin America Today (June 13 – October 1, 2014). Digital Supplements: video of panel
  - Carla Stellweg introductory text for Alfredo Jaar: It Is Difficult, as part of the series Why Art and Architecture today as part of the School of Visual Arts' Art in the First Person lecture series, 2015 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    introductory text by Carla Stellweg for Alfredo Jaar: It Is Difficult, as part of the series Why Art and Architecture Today? at the School of Visual Arts, New York, for the Art in the First Person lecture series (Monday, February 16, 6:30pm). Digital Supplements: Introduction text and invite.
  - Presentation for Jaime Davidovich: Pioneer in Video and Conceptual Art, at New York University's Institute of Fine Arts (2015), 1991 (Box 110, Folder 15)
    Presentation text for Jaime Davidovich: Pioneer in Video and Conceptual Art, a panel discussion at the New York University's Institute of Fine Arts, as part of its Latin American Forum (Monday, May 11, 2015, 6pm) and in conjunction with his solo exhibition, Jaime Davidovich: Forces/Farces, at Exit Art, NY (Speakers included: Julieta Gonzalez, Carla Stellweg, Daniel Quiles, and Sarah Montross. Also included are extra materials relating to Davidovich’s multi-media installation at Exit Art, NY in 1991 called, Forces/Farces: Stations of a New Order (May 29-July 13, 1991). Digital Supplements: video of panel
  - Excelsior Magazine article with Carla Stellweg interview, constructor de identidad by Sonia Avila in commemoration of the 25th anniversary of Fernando Gamboa's passing, 2015 (Box 110, Folder 16)
  - Presentation for Invisible Cities: Raquel Rabinovich and Monika Bravo in Conversation with Carla Stellweg, as part of IDEAS CITY organized by the New Museum with the Y Gallery, 2014-2015 (Box 110, Folder 17)
    Includes notes and text for Carla Stellweg's presentation.
  - Carla Stellweg's Frida Kahlo text, A Testimonial, (unedited and unpublished - scheduled for 2016-2017) for Throckmorton Fine Art, 2015 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    Also includes invites from the Summer 2015 NY Botanical Gardens and Throckmorton Fine Art NY exhibition, Frida Kahlo: Art, Garden, Life, and symposium, Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera: Mexican Art in the 20th Century.
  - Text for, Incomplete Glossary of Latin America, accompanying the exhibition, Esto No Es America, Esta Não é América, This Is Not America, at the Museum of Contemporary Art Detroit with the Kadist Art Foundation, curated by Jens Hoffman and Pablo Leon de la Barra, 2015 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Yearly appointment book, 2008-2009 (Box 110, Folder 20)
  - Yearly appointment book, 2009 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Yearly appointment book, 2010 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Photographs from Carla Stellweg Gallery and personal collection (part 1 of 2), 1993-2009 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Photographs from Carla Stellweg Gallery and personal collection (part 2 of 2), 1993-2009 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Slides with installation shots from La Agencia Gallery, Mexico D.F.; Stellweg-Seguy Gallery and Carla Stellweg Gallery, 1970-1993 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Instituto Nacional de Bellas: taxes and receipts, 1969-1981 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    Instituto Nacional de Bella receipts and taxes paid in Mexico by Carla Stellweg. Includes a Japanese paper portemonnaie
  - Jorge Salazar, 1982-1983 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, insurance info, notes and a 4 x 5 negative regarding the work of artist Jorge Salazar (later sold at Rago Contemporary Art auction in the fall of 2014). Salazar was an artist Carla Stellweg promoted and got a solo exhibition at P.S. 1 (today PS1-MoMA) which in turn landed him a solo show with Germans van Eck Gallery, 420 West Broadway which led later to his exclusive representation with Gallery Ramis Barquet, Fuller Building, East 57th Street and Monterrey, Mexico.
  - Correspondence regarding Julio Galan's family collection, 1982-1983 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    The family collection consisted of a painting of a Raphael replica.
  - Judith Gutierrez, 1982-1993 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    Correspondences with Judith Gutierrez, including letters and photographs along with correspondence with collectors L. Alan Robbins and Juan Castro y Velázquez – both of which purchased Gutierrez’s work from Carla Stellweg Gallery – as well as with registrar Silvia Vega from the Museo de Monterrey, Mexico. Folder also contains shipping receipts, pricelists and exhibition invites.
  - Kate Augenblick, 1984-1986 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    Kate Augenblick pricelist, letters, exhibition invite and correspondence with doctor and collector Thomas S. Schultz regarding her work.
  - Various Carla Stellweg Gallery documents regarding art sales, 1986-2013 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    Includes invoices, related information, slides and photographs. Sold artists include Eugenia Vargas, Jeff Koons, Keith Haring, Diego Rivera, Rufino Tamayo, Elijah Pierce, Roberto Matta, Jose Luis Cuevas, Neal Slavin, Leonora Carrington, Alfredo Castañeda, Andres Serrano, Komar and Melamid, Ray Smith, Hector Garcia, Cildo Meireles, Ana Mendieta, Lola Alvarez Bravo and others.
  - Oweena Fogarty, 1989-1990 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, consignment notes and exhibition pamphlets. The Fogarty pieces are some of the approximately 140 pieces of works from her photography collection that became part of a donation and purchase to Lehigh University Art Galleries in the fall of 2014.
  - Ray Smith, 1990-1993 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    Included are pricelists, consignment forms, photographs and correspondence regarding the work of artist Ray Smith, from Sperone-Westwater; Krasdale Foods; Y-Gallery NY and OMR Gallery, Mexico. Most of these works were sold at Rago Contemporary Art sale in November 2014
  - Ciro Quintana, 1991-1993 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence, faxes, shipping information and invites. Quintana’s pieces from Carla Stellweg’s collection were purchased-sold by Cuban Modern Art scholar and private dealer, Rafael Diaz-Casas.
  - Humberto Castro, 1987-1997 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    Includes correspondences, faxes and articles about Humberto Castro's work. Pieces of Castro's work from Carla Stellweg’s collection were also purchased-sold by Cuban Modern Art scholar and private dealer, Rafael Diaz-Casas.
  - Carlos Zerpa letters, 1989-1992 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    Handwritten letters from Carlos Zerpa - whose early work as a performance artist Carla Stellweg published during the 1970s in Artes Visuales and later Carla Stellweg Gallery handled his work during the 1990s when the artist resided and worked in New York City, all of which were subsequently auctioned at Rago Contemporary Art Sale, November, 2014 (except for a collage work still in Carla Stellweg Collection).
  - Anna Albertina Delgado, 1992 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    Letters to and from Ana-Albertina Delgado as well as a Carla Stellweg Gallery invitational letter to Adriano Buergo to speak about “To Create Art In and Outside Cuba Today,” (Jan. 11, 1993). They were purchased-sold by Cuban Modern Art scholar and private dealer, Rafael Diaz-Casas.
  - Monica Castillo, 1993 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    Consignment letters and information from the OMR Gallery, Mexico, D.F., for two pieces by Monica Castillo, loaned to Carla Stellweg Gallery and subsequently passed on to Grace Borgenicht Gallery and exhibited in a group show of 1990s Neo-Mexican artists. One of these was sold to a Chicago doctor, collector friend of Francine Birbragher (daughter of Celia Sredni de Birbragher founder and owner of ArtNexus).
  - Nestor Quiñones, 1993 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    Consignment letter, faxes and shipping receipt from the OMR Gallery, Mexico, D.F., for triptych by artist Nestor Quiñones, purchased by Carla Stellweg Gallery and sold at Rago Contemporary Art auction in November, 2014.
  - Victor Vasquez, 1993-1995 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    Handwritten notes to Carla Stellweg by Puerto Rican photographer Victor Vazquez. Eight of his photographs that were in Carla Stellweg’s photography collection became part of the donation and purchase to Lehigh University Art Galleries in the fall of 2014. Several other large pieces left with Carla Stellweg Gallery were destroyed in Hurricane Sandy storage flooding.
  - Letter from the secretary of Raymond Page inquiring about Cuban artist Maria Elena Gonzalez, 1994 (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Marta Maria Perez, 1994-1995 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    Correspondences and consignment forms between Carla Stellweg and photographer Marta-Maria Perez Bravo for a group exhibition of women photographs at Carla Stellweg Gallery in 1996. Photographs were sold to a Native-American artist from Arizona, Frank Lapena (1994); and at Miami Art Fair to Egon von Fürstenberg (1995); privately to Pamela Rosenau (1996); and Jerry Suarez (2009).
  - Patricia Martín Briceño and Alberto Tovalin, 1996 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    Carla Stellweg Gallery correspondences with artists Patricia Martín Briceño and Alberto Tovalin. Carla Stellweg owned originally 5-6 Black-and-White photographs, several were included in Lola Alvarez Bravo Plus Modern and Contemporary Mexican Artists, May 3- June 1, 1991; and one was included in the 1990s San Antonio Museum of Art exhibition of Women Photographing Women (with Graciela Iturbide, Sandra Eleta, Lola Alvarez-Bravo etc.). Two were sold to Sandra Cisneros; and two more to a private collector in Austin, Texas. One remains in the Carla Stellweg Collection.
  - Monica Giron, 1996 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    Mónica Girón correspondences and price list. Carla Stellweg purchased three works that were offered at auction and remain unsold at this time, at Rago Contemporary Art sale in November, 2014.
  - Kukuli Velarde, 1996 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    Letter and loan agreement between New Museum and Carla Stellweg Gallery for four pieces by Kukuli Velarde to be included in the exhibition, Labor of Love (Jan. 20 – April 14, 1996), curated by Marcia Tucker for the New Museum.
  - Esterio Segura, 1995-1996 (Box 112, Folder 18)
    Correspondence between Carla Stellweg Gallery and Esterio Segura along with consignment form. Carla Stellweg owns a piece by Segura with sculpture dated 1994 and purchased during the Habana Biennial. See Carla Stellweg Art Inventory on External.
  - Letter to the De Menil Collection promoting Carla Stellweg Gallery artists, 1993, 1999 (Box 112, Folder 19)
    Letter to the De Menil Collection of Houston, Texas, promoting Carla Stellweg Gallery artists Carlos Capelan, Juan Sanchez, Luis Camnitzer, Maria Elena Gonzalez and Jaime Palacios.
  - Segundo Planes, 2001 (Box 112, Folder 20)
    Cuban artist Segundo Planes’s invite for Paternidad: Paintings by Segundo Planes at the Mackey Gallery, Houston, Texas. Planes was part of the Carla Stellweg’s Collection purchased by Cuban Modern Art scholar and private dealer Rafael Diaz-Casas who in turn sold them to his clients. Folder also includes a pricelist.
  - Various art loans, 1992-2011 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    2011 Various art loans and related materials from the collection of Carla Stellweg, including: Aperture Foundation’s exhibition, Lola Alvarez Bravo (September 8-November 2, 2006), a landmark exhibition of work by Mexico’s first great woman photographer, curated by Elizabeth Ferrer; Mary-Anne Martin Fine Art’s consignment of Alfredo Castañeda (sold in 2014 at Morton Subastas, Mexico City; Throckmorton Fine Art’s consignment of Salvador Lutteroth and payment; plus loan and insurance agreements and return of works from the Bronx Museum’s show, Arte no es Vida: Actions by Artists of the Americas, 1960-2000 that included four Eugenia Vargas pieces.
  - Various important catalogs, 2007-2015 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    Important catalogs, invites and exhibition related materials including: the catalog for the 11th Havana Biennial in 2012, Detrás del Muro (Behind the Wall); an invite/program for ArtTable’s 20th Annual Award Ceremony and Benefit Luncheon, honoring Patricia Phelps de Cisneros; checklist for an exhibition at Gallery 151 entitled, A False Horizon: Art from Latin America, curated by PEANA Projects (Aug. 3 – Sept. 3, 2015); an invite to the Smithsonian National Portrait Gallery for the exhibition, Portraiture Now: Staging the Self (Aug. 22 – April 12, 2015; an exhibition brochure for Philippe Parreno’s show H {N)Y P N(Y} OSIS at the Park Avenue Armory (June 11 – Aug. 2, 2015); etc.
  - Invites, correspondence, pricelist and preparatory/research materials for the exhibition, Intimate Portraits of the Immortal Frida Kahlo, at Lincart Gallery, 2008-2009 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    The exhibition used photographs from Carla Stellweg’s Frida Kahlo portraits collection at Lincart Gallery in San Francisco. Included in this folder are scans of letters from Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera (1940), written while Frida was in St. Luke’s Hospital, San Francisco, requesting money from an Alberto and Anita Misrachi, the Misrachi Gallery in Mexico City Central de Publicaciones.
  - Henrique Faria Fine Arts: invoices and receipts, 2010-2013 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    Invoices, checklist, letters and shipping receipts for purchases by Henrique Faria Fine Art, NYC of artists Marta Minujin and David Lamelas, along with an invoice for services rendered for the lodging the artist Oswaldo Macia and guests.
  - Rafael Diaz-Casas consignment forms, 2012 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    Consignment Agreement between Carla Stellweg and private dealer and Cuban modern art scholar Rafael Diaz-Casas for works by artists Ana Albertina Delgado, Nereyda Garcia-Ferraz, Humberto Castro, Ciro Quintana, Tomás Sanchez and Segundo Planes, all of which Rafael Diaz-Casas bought and resold.
  - Ana Mendieta sale to Estrellita Brodsky, 2013 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    Certificate of Authenticity and Invoice as well as scan of check for the purchase of two Ana Mendieta pieces from the Silueta series (1980’s), sold to Estrellita Brodsky.
  - Ana Mendieta, 2014 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    Invoice, receipt of sale, certificate of authenticity and shipping information from the sale of an Ana Mendieta piece that was part of her burned leaf drawing series, from Carla Stellweg’s collection to private dealer and curator Bernardita Mandiola from Chile, who in turn sold it to a private client of hers.
  - Exhibition loan agreement for, Bearing Witness: Art and Resistance in Cold War Latin America, at the John Jay College of Criminal Justice Shiva Gallery, curated by Estrellita Brodsky, 2014 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    Also included is a loan and insurance agreement, plus proof of pickup for the artwork included: the Contra Bienal book from the collection of Carla Stellweg.
  - Materials relating to Rago's November art sale (2014), 1990-1997 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    Including background information on artists Francisco Toledo, Robert Adams, Ray Smith, Arturo Elizondo, José Luis Cuevas, Ismael Vargas and Alejandro Colunga. Includes photographs.
  - Lehigh University Art Gallery, 1990-2015 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    Lehigh University Art Galleries thank you letters, transfer of objects receipt and checklist of all 140 artworks donated by and purchased from Carla Stellweg’s photography collection.
  - Various Artists' catalogs for, The Faraway, Nearby, exhibition of Finnish artists at White Box (2006) (part 1 of 7), 2000-2011 (Box 113, Folder 10)